[ominous music]
Now come clean and admit
your crime, you failure.
What a barbaric,
boring conclusion.
[yelling]
Did you think
a delicate girl like me
would face a barbaric man
like you alone?
[EMILIA] I was hoping Ram was
mistaken about all of this.
[gasps]
Please, tell me
what happened, Subaru.
Why would you do this?
Well-- well, it was--
Maybe he'll feel up
to talking if we introduce
him to my little friend pain.
Wait!
We came to talk to Subaru
since he seemed off!
That's all!
[RAM]
Ms. Emilia, you're too soft.
Don't you remember?
There was a Sin Archbishop
who could take others' forms.
Then couldn't
that Sin Archbishop
taking Barusu's form
be a possibility?
Maybe, but--
I'll make him
tell us everything,
starting with where the
actual Barusu and Meili are.
[gasps] Does that mean
they weren't the ones--
[EMILIA] We can't do this!
- --who moved Meili's body?
How do we decide
whether he's real or not?
[SUBARU]
I lost my memories!
[gasps]
♪ ♪
Now?
After all this?
What kind of game
are you playing?
Ram!
You heard what Subaru said!
There must be
a reason for this!
And Rem?
What happens to Rem?
[gasps]
Stay out of my way!
Tell me again to my face
that you forgot!
No, I-- that's not it.
Tell me with that face
and voice that you forgot Rem.
Say it one more time.
No, don't do it, Ram!
[magic burst]
[grunts]
Damn it!
Ow!
The cage is--
where are Emilia and Ram?
[gasps]
[unsettling music]
♪ ♪
[REID]
Huh?
The hell's up with
this creepy-ass room?
What would make
someone cover a room
with nasty shit
like this anyway?
You freak.
[ominous music]
You're gonna catch flies
if you keep staring like that.
Come on, what's the matter?
You chicken?
You look like you're
gonna start crying.
Hm?
Oh, you get into a fight
with your buddies?
Funny.
Hold on!
You-- you said you were
stuck on the floor above
and couldn't come down
even if you wanted to!
Circumstances change.
Careful what you assume.
But that's just
what you told me.
So how could--
[yelps]
Dumbass.
Don't go thinking
you'll get spoonfed
the answers to everything.
I can leave, so, yeah,
I'm gonna go outside.
Outside of here?
Outside the tower?
But first I gotta clean
up one little regret.
What the hell's
that supposed to mean?
Hey, hold on!
What'll happen with
the exam, then?
[rumbling]
Damn, speak of the devil.
Huh?
[explosion]
[clang]
[roars]
I don't see any
of your other buddies.
Well, guess that makes what
I'm about to do easier.
[clang]
[MEILI] Looks like you've
been handed the perfect chance
to get that guy killed, huh?
And then you'll have another
Book of the Dead to peruse.
[clang]
[gasps]
[beam charging]
[chuckles]
Right behind you!
Julius!
[blast]
[grunts]
Huh. It's a fact that weaklings
don't have a lot of options.
All they can get good
at is making excuses.
[gasps]
Huh?
[thud, splat]
Why are you--
how are you here?
Why are you,
what are you, how are you--
you sound as stupid as your
buddy up there, you know that?
[roars]
Come on, come on,
come on, come on, come on!
[flesh tearing]
Right then,
let's get back to the exam.
Now try to rip this out of my
hands before I get bored, kid.
[exhales]
Huh?
Echidna and Ms. Anastasia
are in your hands!
[gasps]
[REID]
Huh.
Look at that.
Chivalry's not dead
after all, huh?
[clang]
[heavy breathing]
And where do you
think you're going?
Why would you go out of your
way to help that guy anyway?
You rubbed my neck, so what's
with the special treatment?
Subaru!
I was looking for you!
Going that way is
dangerous, I suppose!
[ECHIDNA]
Why are you outside the cage?
Beatrice, get away
from him at once!
It's just as Ram told me.
He isn't the Natsuki
you all know.
[SUBARU]
Ram?
That means I must not have
killed Emilia and Ram, then.
That's not true
in the slightest!
Once I hold his hand,
I'll know for sure, I suppose!
Even if it's not,
he can't be trusted.
I should have obeyed Ana's gut
instinct from the beginning.
I should have come alone.
None of this would have
happened if I'd just listened.
This is my failure.
[SUBARU]
So what if it is?
It doesn't matter!
[gasps]
This tower's done for.
What's gotten
into you, Subaru?
It's not like you
to accept defeat, I suppose.
What exactly is
like me anyway?
Where is the me you guys are
expecting when you look at me?
So you still won't
be honest, pathetically
holding on to the lie that
you lost your memories?
Ram's forgotten
her own twin sister,
and Julius has been forgotten
by every other person,
and you still insist
on keeping up this cruel act?
Act?
You think this is an act?
Are you seriously trying
to say that what I'm doing now
is an act?
If I was that good at acting,
don't you think I'd act out
something better than this?
If I had the privilege
of choosing my own role,
why the hell would I want
to be Subaru Natsuki,
a disgusting,
useless creep like this?
None of you know
a single thing about what
I've suffered through!
Who even am I?
I've lost everything,
everything I've ever known!
I was on my way home from
the convenience store!
Aside from the clerk
working there,
I hadn't talked
to anyone all day!
And suddenly, I'm just in
another world, a tower in sand,
corpses, exams, fakes!
Subaru Natsuki!
This is insanity!
Whatever!
Screw all of you!
I bet you're wondering why
I just suddenly lost my shit,
aren't you?
Well, I reached my limit.
I was pushed too far,
and something in me
eventually snapped!
I can't do anything useful
here, even if I give it my all!
I tried!
So please,
forgive me for failing.
I'm begging you.
Please just let me
go back home already.
If this is God's way of trying
to punish me for something,
then I understand.
I take responsibility
for my actions!
Subaru.
Beatrice, you should go
with him for the time being.
I'll search for Julius myself.
Understood.
Come on.
Subaru, for now just--
[ECHIDNA]
What's the meaning of this?
Explain.
I considered that a compromise.
Why are you
stopping me right now?
Because Julius asked me to.
Stop lying.
[roars]
[gasps]
Incomplete EMT, I suppose!
[magic barrage]
[explosions]
[shrieks]
[gasps]
Natsuki, please don't do
such unpredictable things.
It's confusing.
Like I had enough
time to think.
And my body just moved!
[gasps]
[roars]
El Jiwald!
[blast]
[explosion]
[roars]
[ECHIDNA]
I don't get it.
Just what are you?
What do you hope to accomplish?
Whose side are you on?
I don't have
an answer either.
I really did.
You lost your memories?
You don't even remember
when you took Betty
out of the mansion, I suppose?
I don't.
Sorry.
[BEATRICE] It's fine.
- [gasps]
[BEATRICE]
Even if you've forgotten it,
Subaru, Betty never will.
Not ever.
Let's get moving.
We can't stay here any longer.
Echidna, are you sure?
I still have
my misgivings about you,
but right now I have
to choose my priorities,
a necessary mindset
for a merchant.
By now, I've had plenty
of time to see that myself.
All right, then.
[footsteps]
[roars]
[melancholy music, groaning]
♪ ♪
Enough.
Just--
just leave me here.
Damn it,
damn it, damn it all!
Natsuki, you've done enough.
[SUBARU]
Like hell I have.
Nothing I've done has ever,
ever been enough at all.
I'm not the one you
should worry about.
Shouldn't you help
Beatrice first?
[gasps]
[roar, explosion, shriek]
[grunts]
Oh, I see.
That poor girl was
truly unfortunate.
It hurts.
How it hurts.
Human bodies sure
feel a lot of pain.
Sorry.
I'm sorry.
It's not-- I didn't mean to--
I--
[ECHIDNA] This pain
I feel is the only way
I can ever repay Ana.
It's true, right?
If I returned her
body to her now,
she'd have to feel this pain
and the fear of death
closing in on her.
It's OK.
Don't try to stop it.
I'm ready to fall to hell.
Oh, wow.
Do you hear what she's saying?
I believe this situation is
what they call a windfall.
You're doing
the right thing, Subaru,
putting the poor thing
out of her misery.
Hm?
[heavy breathing]
[groans]
[gasps]
[SUBARU]
You can't--
you can't even do
something that simple,
Subaru Natsuki.
Natsuki,
you can't even lift a rock
to put me out of my misery?
I'm sorry for doubting you.
Why don't you just die?
Yeah, sure.
Why not?
[growling]
[SATELLA]
I love you.
Stop it!
I've had enough of this,
when I don't feel that way!
I've never--
I've never,
ever loved myself.
I already knew
that I was loved.
I knew it!
My mom and dad, both
of them loved me so much
from the bottom
of their hearts.
I knew it.
How the hell could I not?
That's why I wished
I could just disappear.
My parents loved
me so much,
but I could never love
someone as pathetic as me,
someone who
wasn't worth loving!
I love you.
Stop saying that!
Give me a break!
Isn't this enough already?
I love you.
I pretended
I couldn't see it,
but deep down, I already
knew the answer ages ago!
The people who tried so
desperately with all they had,
went out of their way
to show me such kindness!
There's no way they
could be bad people!
And I knew that!
That's why it would
have been better
for everyone if I just died.
If this is the last thing
I can do,
if this can be the end
and Subaru Natsuki
can just disappear--
I love you.
[EMILIA]
That's enough!
[sword slash]
Subaru!
[panting]
[SUBARU]
I'm done.
Huh?
I'm done with this!
Why are you trying
so hard to help me?
Subaru.
[SUBARU]
Something's wrong with you,
you and Julius
and Beatrice, too!
For some reason,
even Echidna was
apologizing to me in the end!
It doesn't make any sense!
Wait, hold on.
In the end?
Subaru, what happened?
Where are Echidna and--
She's dead!
Her legs were blown off.
It was bad.
She lost so much blood!
Beatrice got blown away, too!
[gasps]
And Julius, he told me
to go to take care of them.
Idiot.
They're all idiots.
What exactly are they
expecting me to do?
Take care of them
and get her back?
You're sorry that
you've doubted me?
What are you saying?
The very first time that you
and I met was in the capital
at a place called
the Loot House.
Huh?
[sentimental music]
At the time, my insignia,
which is something
really important to me,
was stolen by Felt.
We knew we had
to find a way to get it back,
and Puck and I were panicking.
Then, once we chased Felt down,
Meili's older sister
came after me.
But you saved my life
as a stranger.
Huh?
That's it.
That's how you and I
first met each other.
Remember?
Also, you were badly
injured while protecting me.
It was rough.
I couldn't leave you, so I took
you back to Roswaal's mansion
with me.
Beatrice healed you there,
although she did complain
about it the entire time.
Then Ram and Rem surely became
good friends with you as well.
And a bit later on,
Meili showed up
without her big sister
and sent mabeasts to do
evil things to us.
It's OK because you
and Ram stopped her.
Roswaal jumped in to take
care of the mabeasts,
and I just stayed home.
That's when we promised
to go on a date together.
Remember that?
♪ ♪
Soon after,
I was called to the capital
for the royal selection,
and you and I got into a
seriously big fight back then.
It was because I didn't
want you to be reckless.
It was hard watching
you get hurt.
And I didn't understand
why you were being so kind
to me either.
I was scared.
So when we fought,
I was sure it was all over.
But when I didn't understand
what was happening
and I found myself trapped
in a precarious situation,
Subaru, you--
you came for me.
And--
♪ ♪
And then you--
you told me something.
You remember?
♪ ♪
Well, I remember all of it,
everything you said for me,
everything you did for me,
and all the promises
for the future.
It's all right here.
I don't remember.
I can't remember any of it.
You-- what's with you,
with all of you?
Who the hell are you
talking about, huh?
Someone capable
of risking his life for others,
someone not
afraid to take action,
someone who won't hesitate
to help those he cares about,
someone who could put his own
life on the line to accomplish
what he puts his mind to?
Don't lie to me!
Someone like that can't
be Subaru Natsuki!
I know better than
anyone just how
pathetic and useless a
human being Subaru Natsuki is,
a good-for-nothing scumbag,
rotten to the core.
Subaru Natsuki is
a good-for-nothing scumbag,
rotten to the core!
I know it!
I know that better
than anyone else!
♪ ♪
Wouldn't it be better
if it wasn't me?
There are plenty of people much
stronger and much smarter, too,
so they should do it instead.
But I can never
be that someone.
I can't.
It's too much.
My name is Emilia,
only Emilia.
There's so much
I need to tell you,
that I need to ask you,
more than you can imagine.
But right now,
tell me one thing.
All I ask is that you
please tell me your name.
Why is it me?
Why does it still have
to be Subaru Natsuki now?
What the hell could he even do?
What are you expecting
from him this time?
What you were saying
before might be right.
There are people who are
much stronger than you.
And I'm sure there are plenty
who are smarter as well.
But no matter what's
happening in my world,
you're the only one
I want to be with.
I hope and believe
that you'll always be
there for me, truly, because--
because if I ever need saving,
I don't want it to be
by someone who does it
because they can
or they're there.
You see, I'd be
a million times happier
if it's by someone I love.
So that was it.
Subaru Natsuki, you were
head over heels in love
with a beautiful
girl like this.
And that love became the source
of your strength, huh?
Give me a break.
Could she be any more
out of your league, bro?
Seriously, where do you
get off aiming so high?
How does a loser like you
end up with a beauty like her?
Again,
my name is Emilia,
only Emilia.
Please, I'd love if you'd
tell me your name.
[sentimental music]
♪ ♪
[gasps]
All right, my name
is Subaru Natsuki,
the man Julius trusted,
Beatrice believed in,
Echidna forgave,
and you, Emilia, hoped for.
If the name of that man who's
earned that is Subaru Natsuki,
then I am Subaru Natsuki.
I want to help Emilia
and everyone else.
I want to save them
from this tower.
If that's something
Subaru Natsuki can do,
I'm going to do it.
Thank you, Emilia, for letting
me believe that for myself.
Subaru, I--
[rumbling, gasps]
♪ ♪
Emilia!
Subaru!
[gasps]
Is this gonna end with us
getting swallowed up by that?
No, this is not the end.
This-- this is going to be
where it finally begins!
I will remember.
I'll remember everything!
Even if you were to forget me,
I'll never forget any of you!
[EMILIA]
Subaru!
Hey, Subaru!
Are you all right?
Oh, what a relief.
I was really worried about you.
[BEATRICE] Emilia,
you need to be firmer with him,
or he won't feel bad
about what he's done.
This time will be different.